export const PHYSICSA2019 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The time rate of increase in velocity is called",
A: "speed.",
B: "force.",
C: "momentum.",
D: "acceleration.",
answer: "D. acceleration",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Which of the following quantities is a vector?",
A: "Speed",
B: "Volume",
C: "Momentum",
D: "Energy",
answer: "C. Momentum.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. In an elastic collision, momentum is conserved as well as",
A: "speed.",
B: "velocity.",
C: "kinetic energy",
D: "potential energy.",
answer: "C. kinetic energy",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The induced current in a coil always flows in a direction so as to oppose the change causing it. This statement is known as",
A: "Ampere’s law.",
B: "Coulomb’s law.",
C: "Lenz’s law.",
D: "Faraday’s law.",
answer: "C. Lenz’s law.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Which of the following instruments can be used to compare the magnitudes of charges on two given bodies?",
A: "Proof plane",
B: "Gold-leaf electroscope",
C: "The electrophorus",
D: "Ebonite rod",
answer: "B. Gold-leaf electroscope",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. A body of mass 2kg is released from a point 100 m above the ground level. Calculate its kinetic energy 80m from the point of release. [g = 10 m s-2]",
A: "900 J",
B: "1600 J",
C: "200 J",
D: "600 J",
answer: "B. 1600 J",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following waves is not mechanical?",
A: "Water waves",
B: "Waves in pipes",
C: "Sound waves",
D: "Radio waves",
answer: "D. Radio waves",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. A loaded spring is set in simple harmonic motion. The force that tends to restore the load to its equilibrium position is",
A: "elastic.",
B: "gravitational.",
C: "frictional.",
D: "adhesive.",
answer: "D. adhesive.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following situations cannot produce total internal reflection? A light ray travelling from",
A: "water to kerosene.",
B: "glass to water.",
C: "water to air.",
D: "Air to water.",
answer: "A. water to kerosene.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The vacuum in a thermos flask reduces heat loss resulting from",
A: "conduction only.",
B: "conduction and convection only.",
C: "radiation only.",
D: "radiation and Convection only.",
answer: "B. conduction and convection only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The diagram above represents an experimental set-up for verifying",
A: "mirror formula.",
B: "lens formula.",
C: "laws of refraction.",
D: "laws of reflection",
answer: "D. laws of reflection",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Which of the following statements about a moving object is correct?",
A: "At a steady speed, the air resistance on it must be equal to zero.",
B: "When accelerating, the resultant force acting on it must be equal to zero.",
C: "There must always be a resultant force acting on it.",
D: "At a steady speed, the resultant force acting on it must be equal to zero.",
answer: "D. At a steady speed, the resultant force acting on it must be equal to zero.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The efficiency of a transformer is 100 %. Which of the following equations would be correct?",
A: "IpEs = IsEp",
B: "NpEp = NsEs",
C: "NsIp = NpIs",
D: "NsIs = NpIp",
answer: "C. NsIp = NpIs",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. A freshly demagnetized bar magnet is placid In East-West direction to ensure that,",
A: "it is affected by the earth’s magnetic field.",
B: "the magnetic domains are within the earth’s field.",
C: "magnetic domains remain randomly arranged.",
D: "magnetic domains are orderly aligned",
answer: "D. magnetic domains are orderly aligned.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Which of the following graphs correctly represents the plot of the charge Q against the potential difference V in a capacitor?",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. ",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. A small amount of air is introduced into the vacuum above the mercury in a mercury barometer tube. The mercury level fails because the air molecules",
A: "cool the mercury and make it contract.",
B: "heat the mercury and make it lighter.",
C: "increase the pressure above the mercury.",
D: "decrease the pressure above the mercury.",
answer: "C. increase the pressure above the mercury",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Calculate the quantity of heat needed to change 60 g of ice at 0.0 °C to water at 80.0 °C. [Specific latent heat of fusion of ice = 3.36 x 105 J kg-1, specific heat capacity of water = 4.2 x 103 J kg-1 K-1]",
A: "22.17 kJ",
B: "40.32 kJ",
C: "4.80 kJ",
D: "20.16 kJ",
answer: "B. 40.32 kJ",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The wire of a platinum resistance thermometer has a resistance of 3.5 Ω at 0 °C and 10.5 Ω at 100 °C. Calculate the temperature of the wire when its resistance is 7.5 Ω.",
A: "57°C",
B: "78°C",
C: "25°C",
D: "36°C",
answer: "A. 57°C",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. A transverse wave of frequency 9 Hz travels 4.5 m in 0.6 s. Calculate the wavelength of the wave.",
A: "1.20m",
B: "3.33m",
C: "0.30m",
D: "0.83m",
answer: "D. 0.83m",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The speed of sound is least in which of the following media?",
A: "Wood",
B: "Air",
C: "Brass",
D: "Water",
answer: "B. Air",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following characteristics of waves can be demonstrated using a ripple tank? \nI. Reflection \nII. Refraction \nIII. Diffraction",
A: "I only",
B: "II only",
C: "I and II only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "D. I, II and III",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of the following graphs gives the correct relationship between energy and mass when mass is converted to energy?",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. ",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. An 800 kg car moving at 80 km h-1 collides with a 1200 kg car moving at 40 km h-1 in the same direction. If the cars stick together, calculate their common speed.",
A: "56 km h-1",
B: "60 km h-1",
C: "8 km h-1",
D: "40 km h-1",
answer: "A. 56 km h-1",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The mass of an object is doubled while the force acting on it is halved. The resulting acceleration of the object is",
A: "doubled.",
B: "quadrupled.",
C: "quartered.",
D: "halved.",
answer: "C. quartered.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. the maximum and minimum thermometer reads the",
A: "maximum temperature during the day and minimum temperature at night from the time it was lest reset",
B: "maximum temperature at night and minimum temperature during the day from the time it was last reset.",
C: "maximum temperature during the day and minimum temperature at night at all times.",
D: "maximum temperature at night and minimum temperature during the day at all times.",
answer: "C. maximum temperature during the day and minimum temperature at night at all times.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. An a.c. generator can be converted to a d.c. generator by replacing the",
A: "commutator with slip rings.",
B: "slip rings with a commutator.",
C: "commutator with an armature.",
D: "armature with a commutator.",
answer: "B. slip rings with a commutator.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which of the following statements is the correct reason for which soft iron is used in making the armature of an electric bell? Soft iron",
A: "retains it magnetism for a long time.",
B: "is a diamagnetic material.",
C: "loses its magnetism easily.",
D: "is not easily magnetized.",
answer: "C. loses its magnetism easily",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Determine the value of x.",
A: "57.2cm",
B: "71.4cm",
C: "10.0 cm",
D: "28.6cm",
answer: "D. 28.6cm",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following devices is used for storing electric charge?",
A: "Capacitor",
B: "Transformer",
C: "Ammeter",
D: "Potentiometer",
answer: "A. Capacitor",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Determine the angular speed of the electron.",
A: "5.22 x1015 rad s-1",
B: "3.28 x 1016 rad s-1",
C: "8.55 x 103 rad s-1",
D: "9.11 x 1013 rad s-1",
answer: "B. 3.28 x 1016 rad s-1",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Calculate the centripetal force acting on the electron.",
A: "1.3 x 10-26 N",
B: "7.7 x 10-47 N",
C: "6.0 x 10-8 N",
D: "3.0 x 10-14 N",
answer: "C. 6.0 x 10-8 N",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. A device consumes 100 W of power when connected to a 120 V source. Calculate its resistance.",
A: "144 Ω",
B: "1.2 Ω",
C: "12000 Ω",
D: "20 Ω",
answer: "A. 144 Ω",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which property of a wave remains constant When the wave travels cm one medium into another?",
A: "Frequency",
B: "Amplitude",
C: "Wavelength",
D: "Velocity",
answer: "A. Frequency",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The anomalous expansion of water occurs in the range",
A: "0 oC to 100 oC",
B: "0 oC to 4 oC",
C: "4 oC to 100 oC",
D: "-4 oC to 0 oC",
answer: "B. 0oC to 4oC",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. A ray of light travelling from a rectangular glass block of refractive index 1.5 into air, strikes the block-air boundary at an incident angle of 30o. Calculate the angle of refraction.",
A: "45.0°",
B: "48.6°",
C: "20.0°",
D: "19.5°",
answer: "D. 19.50",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. A rectangular piece of iron measuring 4 cm x 3 cm at 20°C is heated until its temperature increases by 100°C. Calculate the new area of the meatal of the metal. [Linear expansivity of iron = 1.2 x 10-5 K-1]",
A: "12.0173 cm2",
B: "12.0144 cm2",
C: "12.0346 cm2",
D: "12.0288 cm2",
answer: "A. 12.0173 cm2",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Two bodies of masses 3.0 kg and 2.0 kg are 50 cm apart. Calculate the force of attraction between them. [G= 6.67 x 10-11 N m2 kg-2]",
A: "5.0 x 10 N",
B: "1.6 x 10-9 N",
C: "1.3 x 103 N",
D: "2.3 x 103 N",
answer: "B. 1.6 x 10-9 N",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The diagram above illustrates an object moving in a circular path at constant speed. Which of the arrows correctly indicate the direction of linear velocity?",
A: "W",
B: "Z",
C: "X",
D: "Y",
answer: "B. Z",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of the following thermometers is used to measure the temperature of the human body?",
A: "Platinum resistance thermometer",
B: "Thermocouple",
C: "Alcohol-in-glass thermometer",
D: "Gas thermometer",
answer: "C. Alcohol-in-glass thermometer",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. In the diagram above, the time taken to trace a wave between P and Q is",
A: "1 ½ periods.",
B: "2 periods.",
C: "1 period.",
D: "1 ¼ periods.",
answer: "A. 1 ½ periods.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Which of the following components does not serve as a safety device in electrical circuits?",
A: "Earth wire",
B: "Connecting wires",
C: "Fuse",
D: "Switch",
answer: "B. Connecting wires",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Which of the following liquids has the highest surface tension?",
A: "Oily water",
B: "Soapy water",
C: "Cold water",
D: "Hot water",
answer: "C. Cold water",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The nucleon and proton numbers of a neutral atom of an element are 238 and 92 respectively. Determine the number of neutrons in the atom.",
A: "146",
B: "119",
C: "330",
D: "165",
answer: "A. 146",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. An instrument used to measure relative humidity is the",
A: "manometer.",
B: "hygrometer.",
C: "hydrometer.",
D: "pyrometer.",
answer: "B. hygrometer.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The area under a velocity-time graph represents",
A: "distance.",
B: "speed.",
C: "acceleration.",
D: "moment.",
answer: "A. distance.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Which of the following statements about neutral atom is correct? The",
A: "number of protons is equal to that of electrons.",
B: "core is composed of electrons and protons.",
C: "number of electrons is equal to that of neutrons.",
D: "number of neutrons is equal to that of protons.",
answer: "A. number of protons is equal to that of electrons.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The property that is not exhibited by sound waves is",
A: "reflection",
B: "diffraction.",
C: "polarization.",
D: "interference.",
answer: "C. polarization.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. When ultraviolet light is incident on the surface of certain metals, particles are emitted. These particles are called",
A: "photoelectrons.",
B: "positrons.",
C: "protons.",
D: "photons",
answer: "A. photoelectrons.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Niels Bohr drew certain conclusions about the structure of the atom. Which of the following statements is one of those conclusions?",
A: "The orbit with the least energy is the farthest from the nucleus.",
B: "The allowed orbits contain the same number of electrons.",
C: "Within an atom, there are certain allowed orbits.",
D: "All of the orbits represent the same amount of energy.",
answer: "A. The orbit with the least energy is the farthest from the nucleus.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The graph above illustrates the variation of temperature with time for a solid that is being heated. Which processes take place at the segments P and Q respectively?",
A: "Condensation and evaporation",
B: "Freezing and evaporation",
C: "Evaporation and solidification",
D: "Melting and boiling",
answer: "D. Melting and boiling",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]